<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shibo Chen</title>
    <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shibo-chen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Shibo Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shibo-chen.github.io/media/icon_hu86162c900c18b805235afbee0e76ef56_2947_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Shibo Chen</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Value Proposition for a Computer Architect (TBC)</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/value-proposition-comp-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/value-proposition-comp-arch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I am aiming to graduate and starting the next chapter of my career in industry, it&amp;rsquo;s warranted for me to start to think how I can become a better computer architect. I will decompose it into three categories. The first is domain knowledge, the second is skills, the third is character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each category, I will list what is required, why it is required, and what I should do to acquire those &amp;lsquo;Super Power&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;table-of-content&#34;&gt;Table of Content&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#domain-knowledge&#34;&gt;Domain Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#character&#34;&gt;Character&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;domain-knowledge&#34;&gt;Domain Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;character&#34;&gt;Character&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, a sub-4 marathon</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/sub4marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/sub4marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been dreaming of a sub-4 hour marathon for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sub-4 may not sound hard for many marathon runners as many aim for sub-3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is a good enough goal for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marathons are very interesting endeavors. Many people have run a 5K or maybe a 10K. One might think that a marathon is just eight and a half 5Ks or four 10Ks stacked up together, one after another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, no, no. That couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A marathon requires you to pace yourself within your limit for the first 20 miles (but still as fast as possible), then push yourself and grind for the last 6 miles. This is how I feel this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cramped around the 21-mile mark, around three hours into the race, which was hot, humid, and exposed to unshaded direct sunlight. I was on target for a sub-4 marathon, which would be 30 minutes faster than my previous best record. At that moment, I could have decided to give up and start to walk, as many others on the course did. That&amp;rsquo;s probably what I would have done in the past. After all, if there seems to be no hope of achieving my goal, why bother?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, why do I doubt myself? Have I already given all I have? If not, how can I be sure I will not achieve my sub-4 goal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just kept going. I was slower than before but tried to keep a steady pace. The last 50 minutes were more torturing than the first 3 hours combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did it! 3 hours and 56 minutes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned: Never give up until you have given your all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Depression</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/great-depression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/great-depression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my afternoon nap, when I woke up, I was surrounded by an extreme sense of depression, loneliness, and lostness(if this is a word?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-great-depression&#34;&gt;My Great Depression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few layers of my depression:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first layer is the fact that I am leaving Beijing tomorrow. I grew up in Beijing. I spent so much time here with the City. I have so many family and friends and memories. It&amp;rsquo;s not for good, but the bare flashing of the idea that I am leaving tomorrow leaves me in sorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second layer is that I am so far from where I would like to be at my current age. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good life, but it&amp;rsquo;s not where I would like to be. There is so much work to be done. Do I have the energy to get where I want to be? Not really&amp;hellip;not now. This year, I am starting to analyze where I get my energy and where my energy is going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to follow the herd. I have seen enough people following the herd and getting through the days. Not living their lives but simply getting through the days. I would like to do something more magnificent, but honestly, I am not confident I have what it takes&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-canshould-do&#34;&gt;What I Can/Should Do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I would like to improve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To get a better sense of where my energy goes: to track how much time and attention I spent on each aspect of my life. The awareness of how I spent my time would help me better use my energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep focused: spliting attention is the best way to waste your energy while not achieving anything. Just stay focused. One thing at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dare to say NO: to say NO to non-essential things is to say YES to myself and the more important things. I need to have a better sense of what I would like to achieve in order to prioritize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Blogs</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/writing-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/post/writing-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-writing&#34;&gt;Why Writing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is one of the most effective ways to record, but more importantly, organize ideas. Ideas and sparks, if remain in mind only, stay messy and entangled togehter. It may not make sense at all because it entagnles with emotions. Writing is the best way to get it cleared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also makes sense if I want to share my ideas and thoughts with other people. Good ideas inspires and enboldens people around me and other ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s like throwing out a small fish to bait larger fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-what-language&#34;&gt;In what language?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Chinese studies and works in US, I am a bilingual. Naturally, I am torn between expressing myself in English or Chinese. The differences between the two is that my family may understand Chinese better and I can express my thoughts of more depth with Chinese by quoting from the classics. However, in English I can reach a wider community, a more international one and I would be forced to express ideas in a much more plain manner as English is not my mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I decide to go with English as I think it will carry the ideas further. I will consider pairing my posts with Chatgpt to translate into other languages in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-what-platform&#34;&gt;On what platform?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered many ones. I would ike something accessible to people all over the world and something not actively pushing my posts to people. Rather, the platform should only serve as an archive for people who want to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I end up going with my personal website. It&amp;rsquo;s handy &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-content&#34;&gt;What content?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly focusing on life experience and will include some technical blogs and endurance training experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zipper: Latency-Tolerant Optimizations for High-Performance Buses</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/chen-zipper-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/chen-zipper-2025/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Verification of Low-Trust Architectures</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/tan-severification-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/tan-severification-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twine: A Chisel Extension for Component-Level Heterogeneous Design</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/chen-twine-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/chen-twine-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadowclone: Thwarting and Detecting DOP Attacks with Stack Layout Randomization and Canary</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/shadowclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 16:31:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/shadowclone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Control-flow hijacking attacks have been hard to deploy due to the widespread adoption of control-flow attack defenses such as Control-flow Integrity (CFI). This fact has led to a wide deployment of exploiting non-control data, which are not protected by CFI defenses. Non-control data attacks can be used to corrupt critical data or leak sensitive information. Furthermore, data-oriented programming (DOP) is able to achieve Turing-complete computation capabilities without leaving the control-flow graph of the programs. In this paper, we present a compile time stack layout randomization scheme- Shadowclone -to thwart and detect DOP attacks effectively. Shadowclone generates randomized clones of vulnerable target functions and randomly selects one copy of clones to execute during runtime. In addition, we also insert compile-time random canaries into stack variables and check its integrity before the function returns. In the evaluation section, we show that our approach can thwart and detect DOP attacks efficiently by limiting attacker’s success chance to less than 1%. Shadowclone also has low performance overhead when the program is small and has few function calls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive Into the Cost of Context Switch</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/context_switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 16:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/context_switch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, we are trying to identify the major components of the context swtich overhead on modern CPUs. We showed that data cache misses and d-TLB misses are two major contributors of the overhead. Furthermore, we showed that it requires a non-trivial effort to implement an user-level multithreading library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morpheus: A Vulnerability-Tolerant Secure Architecture Based on Ensembles of Moving Target Defenses with Churn</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/gallagher-morpheus-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/gallagher-morpheus-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alpha-64 Out-of-Order Processor Design</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/alpha64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 16:32:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/alpha64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team implemented a three-way superscalar alpha-64 out-of-order CPU. We are able to achieve 100MHz and IPC of 0.94 with Synopsys 90nm generic library for education under the constraint area requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThundaTag: Disparate Domain Tagging to Enforce Benign Program Behavior</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/thundatag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 16:31:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/thundatag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, we implemented and evaluated the architectural support for domain tagging. Our study shows that such design only requires negligible area overhead and induces low performance overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CommPact: Evaluating the Feasibility of Autonomous Vehicle Contracts</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/erickson-commpact-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/publication/erickson-commpact-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Value of Ensemble of Moving Target Defenses in Morpheus</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/morpheus_ensemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 16:32:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/morpheus_ensemble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work, I studied the average time needed to penetrate a de-featured Morpheus design. The result underscores the robustness of Morpheus defenses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerSpy Upgraded: Location Tracking using Mobile Device Power Analysis</title>
      <link>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/powerspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 16:32:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shibo-chen.github.io/project/powerspy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work, we extended the original Powerspy paper to more environments. Our study shows the availability of attacker using this attack to conduct indoor tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
